JARRAD **ESPINOZA**

(505) 463-3348

flgatr07@gmail.com



OBJECTIVE

Over the past 15 years, I have been employed in a variety of environments that have contributed to my well-rounded work experience. I have excellent written and oral communication skills and consider myself a highly motivated people person. I pride myself on providing excellent customer service and working well with a variety of personality types. I'm interested in securing a career opportunity where I can fully utilize my training and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company.



EXPERIENCE

Customer Advocate II | Blue Cross and Blue Shield of New Mexico SEPTEMBER 2019 – JULY 2022

In this role, I deliver first-call resolution to telephone and written requests while offering exceptional customer service to providers and members who are requesting Prior Authorizations for New Mexico's Government-based program recipients. I utilize interpersonal communication skills and have knowledge of medical terminology, allowing me to make independent decisions on the recourses used to support the health and wellbeing of each member.

Communications Technician | Comcast

APRIL 2015 – SEPTEMBER 2019

I reliably performed service calls including reconnects, disconnects, and changes of service, arriving in a punctual manner to create a positive customer experience from the start. I acted as the face of the company by personally engaging with customers and reviewed all requested services to ensure understanding, agreement, and satisfaction with services provided. As part of my normal job duties, I troubleshot cable issues and served as a technology expert for customers' personal devices, including laptops, tablets, cell phones, etc. I worked independently, made informed decisions, and prioritized effectively, often taking the initiative to sell upgrades, when appropriate, to customer cable packages depending on their specific needs, which went beyond performing typical service duties. In this role, I was required to adhere to Comcast procedures and safe work practices, National Electrical Code (NEC) and National Electrical Safety Code (NESC) requirements, and local ordinances.

Technician | Business Environments

APRIL 2012 - MARCH 2015

I installed high-end office furniture and reconfigured different types of offices using critical thinking and problem-solving skills. In this role, I also inventoried supplies, which required organizational skills and great attention to detail.

Front Desk Coordinator | Rio Rancho Boys & Girls Club

JANUARY 2011 - MARCH 2012

My daily responsibilities included handling cash deposits and billing. I also coordinated the KidTrax program, and effectively communicated with children, parents, and supervisors on issues. I successfully organized and scheduled field trips for the youth and conducted Statefunded programs, such as Smart Kids, Smart Parents.

Peer Support Specialist | Hogares, Inc.

JANUARY 2010 - DECEMBER 2010

I worked closely with teens ages 12-18 experiencing high anger aggression, bipolar disorder, drug and alcohol abuse, suicidal thoughts, and high anxiety. I was involved in the S.A.Y. program with the objective of helping youths make good decisions and continue to do so throughout their lifetimes.

Technician | Alarm Servicing

JANUARY 2009 - DECEMBER 2009

I installed house alarms, cameras, ran wire, and programmed electronics. This position required excellent people skills and salesmanship.

Gym Manager | YMCA

MAY 2008 - JANUARY 2009

I aided with the Homework Help program as well as other after-school programs and served as the gym manager.

Mentor/Computer Technician | Old Town Boys & Girls Club

MAY 2005 - APRIL 2008

I mentored kids ages 5-15 and refereed basketball games. As a computer technician, I ran the computer lab, handled cash deposits and billing, and answered call and questions at the front desk.



EDUCATION

Central New Mexico Community College

2007-2008

Completed pre-requisites

July 2022- Sept 2022

FullStack Web Development

West Mesa High School

2003-2007

Obtained diploma



SKILLS

- Front-end with HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and
 Soft Skills React
- Version control with Git and Github
- Server-side programming with Node.js and Express
- Javascript
- PostgreSQL

- Adaptable to Fast-Changing Environments
- Data Entry
- Ability to Multitask
- Attention to Detail



VOLUNTEERING

Back in my teenage years I volunteered my time to the Old Town Boys & Girls Club since I was 8 years old. I wanted to give back and support the place I spent much of my childhood. The Club played a huge role in helping to keep me out of trouble. I have offered my services to clean, paint, build a playground in the backyard, and work in their snack bar.